<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>kherashanu.com</title>
    <link href="https://kherashanu.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://kherashanu.com" />
    <updated>2024-08-11T22:26:11+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>khera shanu</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kherashanu.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>PySpark for Everyone - Part 0: Why Me?</title>
        <author>
            <name>khera shanu</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kherashanu.com/pyspark-for-everyone-part-0-why-me.html"/>
        <id>https://kherashanu.com/pyspark-for-everyone-part-0-why-me.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://kherashanu.com/media/posts/1/pyspark_post_1_standard.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="PySpark"/>
            <category term="Data Engineering"/>
            <category term="Apache Spark"/>

        <updated>2024-02-02T22:10:00+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kherashanu.com/media/posts/1/pyspark_post_1_standard.png" alt="Transision from Backend dev to DE" />
                    Before diving into the world of big data and PySpark, let me&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://kherashanu.com/media/posts/1/pyspark_post_1_standard.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Transision from Backend dev to DE" /></p>
                
  <p>
    Before diving into the world of big data and PySpark, let me introduce myself and explain why I believe I can guide you through these concepts effectively.<br><br>For nearly a decade, I worked primarily as a backend developer. Although I dabbled in various other roles, backend development always felt like my true calling. Interestingly, I began working with data engineering tasks before I even knew the term existed. My official transition to data engineering occurred while I was a Senior Software Engineer at a Silicon Valley company called Nextroll.<br><br>Our team at Nextroll had minimal "typical" backend work. We mostly fixed each other's bugs or added minor features. However, a sudden influx of data engineering tasks led our entire backend team to shift focus. For over a year, I performed data engineering duties without holding the official title.<br><br>Backend engineering started to feel monotonous to me. While scaling a product for a billion users in a cost-effective and resilient manner is undoubtedly cool and challenging, such opportunities are rare. I realized that data and AI represent the future. Data engineering seemed like the perfect avenue to combine my passion for backend development with a role more resilient to future changes. I am optimistic about AI's potential in the next decade, and I believe backend roles may become more specialized and automated. In contrast, data engineering is a field where ten different people might give you ten different definitions.
  </p>

  <p>
    Nextroll faced tough times due to the deprecation of third-party cookies in Chrome, which led to many layoffs, including mine. I saw this as the perfect opportunity to officially switch to a data engineering role. Currently, I work remotely for a company that allows me to support BP (British Petroleum). Remote work is crucial for me.<br><br><b>Why am I, a relatively new data engineer, the right person to guide you?</b><br><br>I bring a unique perspective. Having worked in various environments and roles, I can view data engineering from a broader angle that many seasoned data engineers might not. I consider myself a competent programmer with a solid understanding of fundamental computer science principles and Python.<br><br>I know self-promotion can be off-putting, but it's essential for you to trust me as we embark on this journey together. <em>Shall we begin?</em>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
